comlaw.gov.au 2016-02-03

# ComLaw - Privacy

This privacy policy applies to personal information that may be collected by or on behalf of the ComLaw team as part of managing ComLaw.

We are serious about protecting your privacy, and we encourage you to take action as appropriate to protect yourself from the inherent risks of internet use.

Our website may contain links to other websites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. When you go to other websites, we advise you to read their privacy policy.

**Personal information**

Personal information is information or an opinion, whether true or not, about a person whose identity is apparent, or reasonably ascertainable, from the information or opinion.

The ComLaw team may ask for personal information such as your email address if you send us a message or if you ask for customised services such as "notify me when" emails. Usually we will ask you for such information. We may use other sources such as the internet or a phone directory if required, for example, to confirm important information.

**Use and disclosure of personal information**

If you choose to provide your personal information to the ComLaw team, we only use it for the purpose(s) for which you gave it to us and for related, internal management purposes. We do not disclose your personal information to anyone else unless:

  * you consent to or expect disclosure of your personal information 
  * disclosure is necessary for the enforcement of the criminal law or for the protection of public revenue 
  * disclosure is necessary to prevent or lessen a serious and imminent threat to the life or health of a person, or 
  * disclosure is required or authorised by law. 

**Your choices**

You can access and ask us to correct personal information that we hold about you. If you have registered to use My ComLaw, you can opt out of further contact from us on a temporary or permanent basis by updating your My ComLaw profile.

**Cookies**

To improve your experience on our site, we may use 'cookies'. Cookies are an industry standard and most major web sites use them. A cookie is a small text file that our site may place on your computer as a tool to remember your preferences. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website.

**Website analytics**

Our website uses Google Analytics, a service which transmits website traffic data to Google servers in the United States. Google Analytics does not identify individual users or associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. We use reports provided by Google Analytics to help us understand website traffic and webpage usage.

By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner described in [Google's Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/) and for the purposes set out above. You can opt out of Google Analytics if you disable or refuse the cookie, disable JavaScript, or [use the opt-out service provided by Google](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

**More information**

The ComLaw team is part of the [Office of Parliamentary Counsel](http://www.opc.gov.au/)  (OPC). The Office is bound by the Information Privacy Principles of the _Privacy Act 1988_ in relation to the collection, storage, use and disclosure of personal information. ComLaw also follows the [Privacy Commissioner's Guidelines for Federal and ACT Government Websites](http://www.privacy.gov.au/materials/types/guidelines/view/6057) .

This is a summary of the ComLaw team’s personal information handling practices. If you need more information or if you wish to access or update the information we hold about you, please contact us.

If you have any concerns about our personal information handling practices, please contact the Offices's [Privacy Contact Officer](mailto:comlaw@ag.gov.au). Further assistance and information on privacy is also available from the [Office of the Australian Information Commissioner](http://www.oaic.gov.au/)  (OAIC).

This summary statement has been developed from material prepared by the former Office of the Privacy Commissioner (now part of OAIC).
